the most profitable skill ever or as
many people know it trading this allows
Ordinary People to generate anywhere
from $1,000 to $1,500 a week as a
beginner Trader using my set and forget
strategy and in the next few minutes I'm
going to explain to you how to master
the same tools that I use every single
day when I trade it makes absolutely no
difference whether you have experience
your trading or you don't you're a
beginner experience doesn't matter and
the first thing is the charts these
charts are the place where we can see
the real life price of absolutely any
asset in real time this means that we're
able to see if a stock currency pair
commodity what the price is at the
current price in real time we can
identify if it gets cheaper or more
expensive knowing this is very important
but do you really want to know how money
is generated in these markets so the
best way to understand this is where are
these profits coming from because it
can't be coming from thin air so where's
the money actually being made from and
as crazy as it might sound it actually
comes from somebody else's pocket let me
explain this means that what one person
loses in the market somebody else is
making that same exact figure so the
money is not made from thin air what
somebody loses in the market somebody
else gains if I won $20,000 today
trading that means that a person a
business somebody El in the financial
Market has lost $20,000 so now that you
know where the money comes from let me
explain to you guys the exact actions
you should take in the markets in order
to make money and this is very simple
I've divided it in two parts and the
first one is to understand if the market
is headed to the upside or if it is
headed to the downside so you understand
the trend of the market so you know if
you want to buy or if you want to sell
and the second one is right after you
know whether you want to buy with the
markets or if you want to sell based off
of the trend of the markets the second
step is to actually take the trade so
for the first action what you will need
is a tool to mark up price just as we
saw at the beginning of this video the
one that I personally use and I think
99% of the the industry is trading view
on this page you'll be able to see the
price of any commodity any currency any
crypto in real time it is very easy and
very user friendly so now that you're on
trading view you need to get the
currency per that you want to trade for
example let's say the euro dollar or as
many people know it Euro USD so now once
you've added this to your watch list
whether you've given it a color blue red
purple green whatever color you want now
you can see the real time price of the
euro versus the dollar you can see the
progress in different time frames so
there time frames such as the daily time
frame 4 Hour 2 Hour 1 hour 30 minute
meaning that each of these candlesticks
is the time frame that you have been
selected on so for example here we are
on the daily Candlestick so means every
single one of these candlesticks is a
day 24 hours for each one of these
candlesticks if we go down to the 4 Hour
every single one of these candlesticks
is 4 hours you can see it to the bottom
right of the screen how the price of the
market tells you how much time is left
within that Candlestick to close and the
next step is to actually do the analysis
or also known as top down analysis where
you mark up your charts this is where
you see a bunch of lines and a bunch of
boxes and this is to identify key points
to where you're going to enter the
market so you can anticipate where the
market is going to go to the upside or
go to the downside and this is exactly
what I'm going to be explaining in my
next video so how do you break down the
charts professionally as I do it how to
properly understand top down analysis
time frame correlation currency pair
comparing all of this where I am able to
predict what the market is going to do
pretty much all the time so let me do a
quick recap Once you go to trading view
you want to add a curreny pair you just
type it up then you can add it and make
sure to use the oanda server because
this is the server that doesn't have any
gaps if you use fxcm if you use
forex.com you're going to have gaps in
the way you see the charts oanda.com is
the only server that there is no gaps in
the markets and this is going to help
you a lot as a beginner Trader so you
don't get confused on what these gaps
are after you add the currency pair of
your wish then you can add it to your
watch list based off of the color that
you want to add it so then there you can
confirm what Market you want to trade
based off of the color and this is a
very brief summary of how you will use
trading view to analyze the markets that
you are interested in trading in this is
what I do every single day when I come
to the markets now that you understand
the currency pairer that you want to
trade you understand where it is in real
time price you understand whether you
want to buy or sell now it's time to
actually take execution on the trade so
you can trade real time and make real
money on the prediction that you're
about to make on this currency pair and
this is exactly what metatrader is metat
Trader 4 or metat Trader 5 they're
pretty much exactly the same thing I
personally use both metat trater 4 think
about it as an iPhone 8 and then metat
trater 5 think of it of the new iPhone
11 they both have the same function but
obviously the iPhone 11 is just much
newer and has cooler features but they
both do the same exact thing in order to
access one of these accounts on this
platform you need to have the
credentials to do so so you're going to
actually be able to use it and execute
the trades that you're about to predict
and these credentials are going to be
given to you by the broker of your
choice and I'm going to give you two
different options of what you can do in
your broker first option is you can go
on and deposit money once you deposit
the money into your broker of your
choice please do your due diligence
before selecting your broker and then
after you deposit the money you can then
go on to the broker they will provide
you credentials to metatrader 4 or
metatrader 5 whichever one of you're
liking and then you are trading real
time assets where you can c capitalize
off of these markets or you can go to
the broker of your choice and instead of
depositing real money you can paper
trade also known as demo trading simply
so you can get used to trading the
currency pairer that you're going to use
or also as well to test the type of
market conditions the broker is
providing you with and since it's demo
or paper trading it's absolutely free
zero cost for you so once you have
chosen one of these two options the
broker will then give you the
credentials so you can log into
metatrader 4 or metat Trader 5 so you
can take execution of the prediction
you're going to do on the currency pair
once you enter the credentials you
should see the initial balance of your
account whether you opened a real
account or a demo account the first
thing you see is the balance of your
account so once you're here in the app
the first thing that you have to do is
you have to add the Commodities or the
currency pairs that you're actually
trading that you're predicting on
trading view now you need to add it on
Med Trader 4 and medit trator 5 it's
very easy all you have to do is go to
the top right corner and then select the
pairs that you want to add your broker
is going to have a list of different
types of groups that your currency pairs
Commodities cryptos are in so after
you've added the pairs that you've been
analyzing now to your watch list on
metatrader as well this is where you
simply click on the currency pair where
you can take execution on Real Time
Market immediately before taking the
trade there's three different types of
orders that you can do the first one is
going to be a market execution meaning
that the moment you click buy or the
moment you click sell you're going to
enter the trade at that very second the
second is a buy stop or a sell stop
meaning the moment price breaks through
a point and it gets to there it will
automatically get you into the market
you have to do absolutely nothing you
just place the area where you want to
enter the trade where you want your buy
stop to be activated or your sell stop
once price gets there it will then do
that and then the third option is buy
limits or sell limits which is very
similar to a buy stop or sell stop once
price gets to that certain point that
you predicted it to it will enter you
into the trade immediately and this is
what a lot of Traders use in order for
them to not take a trade immediately in
the market executions because they are
predicting for price to get to a certain
points without them actually looking at
the markets so after you decided what
type of Market execution you want to do
then next is the lot size lot siid is
also known as how much are you going to
risk per trade and this is very key to
trading because you want to have proper
risk management and don't think you
could just go in and put whatever lot
size you want the leverage that you have
on your account is going to limit you on
the lot size that you can use and this
is is done for your own benefit so you
don't over risk or over leverage your
account which will cause for you to end
up losing your money after you've
selected your lot size then you have to
put your takeprofit area where is it
that you want to get out on the trade
that you believe that is the right Zone
whether you are selling price you want
to get out at a certain Zone whether you
are buying price you want to get out at
a certain Zone and then last but not
least which is by far the most important
it is your stop loss this is where you
want to get out of the operation if
price gets to that area because because
it means that you are completely wrong
on your trade I highly recommend every
single Trader out there to use a stop-
loss and I can't stress this enough so
once you've added your currency pair
you've added your lot size the type of
Market execution that you want your take
profit your stop loss you are ready to
place your trade and this is simply
where you will select this buy button or
this sell button which will enter you
into the market immediately and as soon
as you click it like that you're in the
market and you'll be able to check the
progress of your trade whether you are
in a profit or or any loss in this
middle section right here here you can
see if you're trade if it is about to
hit your take profit or if it is about
to hit your stop loss and that has been
all for this video for now you want to
know more about my C forget strategy
that literally generates me numbers like
these or like these every single week in
the financial markets and it allows
absolutely anybody to generate anywhere
from $1,000 to $1,500 a week as a
beginner Trader using my set and forget
strategy with only 3 months literally
starting from zero not knowing what
trading is just click the link in the
description below I have a video for you
there that will explain in great detail
what I am about and the number one
trading Community is about so thank you
guys for watching the video all the way
to the end I hope you guys like this
video and stay tuned to the next one see
you guys